Guide to the Fanny Simon Papers TAM.185
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Latin American Education and Organizing, 1920s-1984
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT) (Box 5, Folder data_value_missing_8f7259a6eb8a9562fc725e2762b92270)
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT), Trip to Caribbean and United States, American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD) Names and Students, 1959-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Other Unions: Streetcar Workers of Mexico City, Tampico Organization Yucatan Railroad, Catholic Railroad, 1920s (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Partido Izquierda Radical, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Penalver, Manuel, "Cooperacion y Coordinacion en Materia de Educacion Obrera", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Peron in Power and in Government" and "Struggle in Spain for a Peaceful Democratic Transition", undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Porras-Calderon, Renee, Areas of Labor Education in Latin America, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - "Por Qué?" Revista Independiente, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - "Report of the First Inter-American Conference of Directors of Labor Education Held by ORIT", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Republic of Cuba, Land Reform Law, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Research Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 18-28)
  - Research Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
  - Research Notes: Chile, Haya de la Torre, Uruguay, Brazil, Fraternidad, Argentina, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Research Notes: Peru, Haya de la Torre, Communist Movement in Latin America, Argentina, Cuba, El Salvador, Hondoras, Mexico, Amanta, Bolivia, Chile, Ecuador, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Research Notes: Argentina, Brazil, Ecuador, Costa rica, Colombia, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Research Notes: Venezuela, Ecuador, Mexico, Colombia, Chile, Carlos Keller, Puiggros, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Research Notes: Puiggros, McBride, Chile, Phelps, Colombia, Royal Institute, Paraguay, Argentina, Garcia Calderon, Ecuador, National Bureau of Economic Res. International Migrations, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Research Notes: United Fruit Co., Justicia, Chile, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Research Notes: Wages, El Socialista, United Fruit Co., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Research Notes: Argentina, Chile, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Research Notes: Chile, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Research Notes: Noticiario Obrero Interamericano, Hisp. Amer. Report, Recabarren, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Research Notes Likely for "Recabarren and the Labor Movement of Chile", undated (Box 6, Folder 18-20, Box 7, Folder 1-15)
  - Rodriguez, Leonidas, "Participacion Popular y Desarrollo Economico", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Rural Community Development and Organized Labor", undated (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
  - Sanchez, P.Urbano, "Promocion Familiar en los 'Pueblos Jovenes' de Lima", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Senior, Clarence, "Current Happenings in Mexico", Nov 1939 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Servicio Cooperativo Interamericano de Education (SCIDE) Outline, circa 1957 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Servicio de Prensa Obrera Campesino (SOCI), 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Simon, Fanny, "A Critique of Pierre Schori's Central American Dilemma", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Simon, Fanny, "Latin America=What Kind of Revolution?", undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Simon, Fanny, "Luis Emilio Recabarren and the Labor Movement of Chile", circa 1949 (Box 7, Folder 25-28)
  - Simon, Fanny, Draft of "Luis Emilio Recabarren and the Labor Movement of Chile", circa 1949 (Box 8, Folder 1-2, Box 7, Folder 29-30)
  - Simon, Fanny, "The Military Coup in Chile", undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sinamos, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Sindicato Nacional de Trabajadores de la Educacion", 1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sindicato Trabajadores de la Standard Fruit Company, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sindicato Unico de Trabajadores en la Educacion del Peru (SUTEP), 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Socialista Democratico Guatemala, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Solidaridad Internacional Obrera, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Solidarity with the Unions of Chile", undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Some Actions and Situations that Violate the Human Rights of the Miskito, Sumo, and Rama Indians of the Atlantic Coast of Nicaragua", 1982 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Survey of Curriculums in the National and Regional Trade Union Education Centers of the AIFLD", 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Trabajo", Dec 1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Unveiling Cuba", undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Uruguay, Confederacion Uruguaya de Trabajadores, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Uruguay, Socialismo Autentico Pamphlets, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Uruguay, Clippings, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Vargas, Getulio. "Brasil el P.T.B. Carta de Lisboa", undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Venezolano de Mujeres, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Vernengo, Roberto, "Libertad Sindical y Relaciones de Trabajo en America Latina: I", 1955 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Windmuller, John P., "Administrative Problems of the International Labor Movement", 1960s (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Series III: Spanish Education and Organizing, 1957-1984
  This series contains clippings, pamphlets, articles, and other materials related to Spain under the Franco government, from the 1960s to the 1980s. The majority of the materials focus on the Socialist Party under Franco.
  - Eighth Congreso del Partido Socialista Obreroespanol", 1961 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Iberica for a Free Spain, 1966, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Resumen, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Spain: Clippings, Notes, Union General de Trabajadores de Espana Materials, 1957-1966 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Spain: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Press Releases, "Arrests and Justice in Franco Spain", 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Spain: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Press Releases, Correspondence, Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Spanish Socialist Workers Party (PSOE) Congress, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - "The Schools in Franco Spain", 1967 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Torroba Bernaldo de Quiros, Felipe, "The Spanish Jews", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Workers under Franco, 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Series IV: Political Activities, 1964-1989
  This series mostly contains conference proceedings from International Council of Social Democratic Women, Social Democrats USA, and the Socialist International Congress in the 1970s and 1980s. It includes meeting minutes, speeches, correspondence, handwritten notes, circulars, reports, and memoranda from the Socialist International National Action Committee. The majority of materials Simon saved from conferences often relate to events and activities happening within the Socialist Party in Latin America. Simon was active in promoting female leadership in Socialist Party, and worked to promote that through conferences and the International Women's Year and her involvement in Social Democratic Women and Socialist International Women.
  - Caracas, Meeting, Socialist International Women, UN Decade of Women, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Commission on the Status of Women United Nations Economic and Social Council, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Reunion of the Norman Thomas Presidential Campaign, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Fourteenth Post-War Congress of the Socialist International - General Circular, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 34-36)
  - International Council of Social Democratic Women, 1970-1978 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - International Council of Social Democratic Women, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - International Council of Social Democratic Women, Conference Materials, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - International Council of Social Democratic Women, Speech by Reimund Seidelmann, Bureau Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - International Council of Social Democratic Women, Tenth Conference, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - International Women's Year, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Simon to Irmtraut Leirer, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Second National Women's Conference, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Social Democrats, International Reports (Latin America), 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Social Democrats, USA, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Social Democrats, USA, El Salvador, Eastern Europe, and Memoranda, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Social Democrats, USA National Convention, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Affairs International Council of Socialist Women Bulletin Correspondence, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Socialist International, 1972-1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Socialist International Congress (including National Action Committee materials), 1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Socialist International Congress, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Socialist International Congress, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Socialist International Congress, Introductory Report by Leopold sedar Senghor, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Socialist International Congress, Proceedings, Bureau Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Socialist International Congress, Programme and Papers Presented, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Socialist International Congress, Speeches by Carlos Andres Perez, Willy Brandt, Felipe Gonzalez, Leopold Sedar Senghor, Ichio Asukata, Bruno Kreisky, Kalevi Sorsa, Mario Soares, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Socialist International Meeting Minutes, Program, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Socialist International, Press Releases, Reports from Meetings, Presentation, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Socialist International, Speeches and Resolutions and International Council of Social Democratic Women, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
  - Socialist International Women, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Socialist International Women, Finnish Social Democratic Women, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Socialist International Women, Bureau Meeting in London, Conference in Madrid, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Socialist International Women Conference, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Socialist International Women, Conference "How Can We Defend Peace", 1982 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Socialist International Women, Minutes and Conference Materials, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Socialist International Women, Seminar on Socialism and Feminism, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Socialists Organizations Response to Chilean Coup d' Etat, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Statement by the International Council of Social Democratic Women to the Commission on the Status of Women, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Swedish Social Democratic Party, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - United Nations Conference of International Women's Year, circa 1980 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - United Nations Decade for Women Poster, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - United Nations NGO Committee on Aging and Retired Teachers Chapter, 1980, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Women and the Labor Movement US and Abroad, Mostly National Commission on the Observance of International Women's Year, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Women Workers, US and International, 1964-1974 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Series V: United States Labor Organizing Materials, 1940s-1989
  This series is comprised of research and educational materials for Simon's labor educator classes and her work with the Workers Defense League and Coalition of Labor Union Women. Materials in this series include clippings, circulars, and other materials.
  The majority of the series also includes materials related to the United Federation of Teachers (UFT), including correspondence and memoranda related to the union's protest against the New York City Board of Education's bilingual testing program in 1975, correspondence from teachers outlining curriculum of the bilingual programs in their schools to the union, and the response of the union to ASPIRA v. the New York Board of Education. Other materials related to UFT include lobbying for a higher budget for schools, reports of discrimination by minority teachers to the Office of Civil Rights in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, and the treatment of union members in the Panama Canal Zone after 1979.
  - American Union History, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bilingual Programs, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 2-10)
  - Budget Coalition: Emergency City-wide Committee, 1970-1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Budget Coalition: Coalition for Full Funding of Public Schools, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Budget Coalition, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 13-15)
  - Circulars and Meeting Minutes: Workers Defense League, New York City Youth Employment Coalition, Mobil Report, Bureau of Public Affairs, UFT, 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women, Convention Materials, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Coaltion of Labor Union Women, "Women at Work" Convention, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Current Problems, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Recommendations for the New York City Board of Education's Response to the US Office of Civil Rights Allegations of Employment Discrimination, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, New York City School System Employment Practices Review, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Deposition Affirming Ruth Schechter Gold's Activities Against Communism in Teachers Union, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Education Material in LA (Notes), undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Fiscal Crisis, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 29-30)
  - Hewes, Amy, "Early Experiments in Workers' Education", 1956 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Kolodny, Jules: Canal Zone, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
  - Labor Politics, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Methods and Techniques of Workers' Education" Filmstrip No. 1, undated (Box Shared Tamiment A007)
  - Nash, Al, "Handbook of Action Methods for Teachers", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - "Planning an Education Program for the Local Union: Education for Members, Stewards, Business Agents, and Staff" Program Planning, Letters, and Contracts, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Retired Teachers in United Federation of Teachers and American Federation of Teachers, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Schwartz, Philip J., "Coalition Bargaining", 1969 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Song: "Devotion, Solidarity, and Honor", undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Twentieth-Fifth Anniversary Teacher Union Dinner Dance, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Unemployment Compensation and Short-Time Compensation", undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - United Federation of Teachers/American Federation of Teachers, 1986, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - United Federation of Teachers Women's Rights Committee, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - United Federation of Teachers Women's Rights Committee, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Workers Defense League, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Workers Defense League Golden Anniversary Journal, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Workers Defense League: Minutes, Agenda, and General Matters, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Workers Instructors Course, undated (Box 11, Folder 25-26)